<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Peoples on Marine Microbial Macroecology Lab</title>
    <link>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Peoples on Marine Microbial Macroecology Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/benner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/benner/</guid>
      <description>Title: Dr Ina Benner Status: hidden

I am interested in understanding how single cell organisms can evolve to changes in climate.
Presently I am determining the potential of arctic phytoplankton to evolve to changing temperature.
For my PhD I worked on the utilization of organic nutrients in phytoplankton at the Alfred Wegner Institute in Bremerhaven, Germany. I&amp;rsquo;ve also worked at the Romberg Tiburon Center for Environmental Studies in San Francisco on the adaptation of calcifying phytoplankton to temperature and carbon dioxide concentration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/brown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/brown/</guid>
      <description>Title: Dr Chris Brown Status: hidden

I am interested in biochemical processes that dramatically alter the environment, such as photosynthesis, nitrogen fixation, metal detoxification and methanogenesis.
Presently I am working on quantitative methods for proteins, carbohydrates, and nucleic acids. I also operate a small biotech company that I founded with two colleagues, called Environmental Proteomics. We develop proteomics tools and methods for plant sciences, oceanography, and a variety of microbial processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/daly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/daly/</guid>
      <description>Title: Margaux Daly Status: hidden

I am interested in understanding how phytoplankton respond to changing arctic conditions. I am currently working to understand how changes in environmental conditions such as light and temperature influence the evolutionary potential of Arctic and Antarctic Phaeocystis species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/faulkner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/faulkner/</guid>
      <description>Title: Sally Faulkner Status: hidden

I am interested in understanding how the macromolecular composition of microalgae is related to environmental and biotic conditions.
Presently I am studying the effect of nitrogen and phosphorus limitation on macromolecular composition of a size range of centric diatom species.
For my BSc I am completing a double major of Biology and Environmental Science (Hons.). I have a strong interest in biological oceanography, geology, and theatre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/fiset/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/fiset/</guid>
      <description>Title: Catherine Fiset Status: hidden

I am a fourth-year honours student in biology. I am interested in how variations in the macromolecular composition of micro- and macroalgae impact marine ecosystems.
In the last year, I have done research on macroalgae. I first looked at the biases in the methods used to quantify macroalgae macromolecular content, and am now investigating the differences in average macromolecular composition between the three macroalgae phyla: the Chlorophyta, Rhodophyta, and Ochrophyta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/fyfe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/fyfe/</guid>
      <description>Title: Matthew Hamilton Fyfe Status: hidden

I&amp;rsquo;m interested in the macromolecular content of phytoplankton, and am spending the summer learning the techniques for determining such data. I will be applying this knowledge to the diatom Didymospenia geminata once we&amp;rsquo;ve extracted samples of it from New Brunswick rivers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/garg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/garg/</guid>
      <description>Title: Aneri Garg Status: hidden

I am interested in the cellular macromolecular composition of phytoplankton, and how various taxa change their composition during and after periods of environmental stress.
Currently I am quantifying the macromolecular composition of the species Micromonas at various points along its growth cycle. This microalgae has a broad pan-Arctic distribution and is present throughout the year. Their ecology and composition will be particularly important to track in response to arctic climate change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/hammond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/hammond/</guid>
      <description>Title: Thomas Hammond Status: hidden

I am interested in the statistical processes which are required for genome sequence analysis and how phytoplankton adapt when exposed to oil rich environments. I am currently working on reconciling the variances in data reporting and recording from the many different phytoplankton collection centers across the world.
I am a recent graduate of Mount Allison and am looking to discover the various fields which can benefit from regression and time series analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/houinato/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/houinato/</guid>
      <description>Title: Kindy Houinato Status: hidden

I am a fourth-year student completing an Honour in Economics and a Major in Environmental Science. This summer, I am interested in understanding the advantage and disadvantages associated with the different chains formed by diatoms. Literature suggests that the shape and length of chains appear to be determined by several environmental factors, such as effectiveness of grazer defense (Sournia 1982; Smetacek et al. 2004; Bergkvist et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/hu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/hu/</guid>
      <description>Title: Dr Ruby Hu Status: hidden

As a chemist, my expertise covers a broad spectrum of capabilities including (1) chemistry, such as inorganic nanoparticles, organic synthesis, analytical chemistry especially the nitrate optode in microplate and analysis of biogenic silica; (2) biology, such as purification and taxonomy of fossilized diatom in sediment, culturing, automate fossilized diatom sample analysis with FlowCam.
My new goal is to learn more about assay analysis of microalgal cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/laforest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/laforest/</guid>
      <description>Title: Justin Laforest Status: hidden

I am interested in researching the effects of global climate change on marine phytoplankton, to analyze the resulting climate feedbacks related to global carbon fixation.
Presently I am researching different traits amongst marine diatoms in effort to determine why some diatoms form chains, in conjunction to the method in which they do so. Understanding the reasoning of chain forming diatoms will provide further information of diatom life cycles, and their predicted future success within the effects of a globally changing climate system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/liang/</guid>
      <description>Title: Dr Yue Liang Status: hidden

I am interested in understanding physiological and biochemical responses in microalgae to environmental changes using systemic biological approaches.
Presently I am working on RNA-seq based transcriptomic analyses on two closely related diatom strains cultured under three different temperatures.
For my PhD, I studied useful natural microalgal lipids on several aspects including structural characterization, biosynthesis pathway identification, and investigation of their metabolic regulation under stressed conditions at Tokyo University of Agriculture and Technology in Japan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/liefer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/liefer/</guid>
      <description>Title: Dr Justin Liefer Status: hidden

I am interested in the physiology and ecology of aquatic microbes, including their production of toxins or useful natural products.
Presently I am studying how differences in macromolecular composition and energy storage among microalgae affect their growth and stress tolerance.
For my PhD, I studied coastal biogeochemistry, phytoplankton ecology, and toxic algal blooms at the Dauphin Island Sea Lab in Dauphin Island, USA. I continued this work as a postdoctoral researcher at the Univ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/mcginty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/mcginty/</guid>
      <description>Title: Dr Niall McGinty Status: hidden

I&amp;rsquo;m broadly interested in marine spatial ecology and time series analysis of pelagic ecosystems ranging from the micro- to the macroscale. I am particularly interested in the ways in which organisms (especially zooplankton) respond to changes in the climate regarding their distribution, niches and timing.
My PhD was conducted in the NUI Galway where I examined the regional scale variability of plankton within Irish waters over the last 50 years, and tried to put into context these findings with the large scale shifts observed across the North Atlantic during that time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/mei/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/mei/</guid>
      <description>Title: Dr Zhi-Ping Mei Status: hidden

I am a biological oceanographer interested in understanding how plankton communities in marine and aquatic ecosystems form and change with environmental change due to natural or anthropogenic disturbance, and its consequence to the biogeochemical processes of the ecosystems.
I use quantitative approaches to mining the observational data, and build models to investigate the diversity and structure of plankton communities in a changing environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/mutshinda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/mutshinda/</guid>
      <description>Title: Dr Crispin M. Mutshinda Status: hidden

I am interested in the interplay of random drift and niche-mediated (non-neutral) processes in driving the dynamics and structure of ecological communities.
Currently I am designing hierarchical Bayesian models and Markov Chain Monte-Carlo algorithms to identify potential trait-based phytoplankton clusters and investigate whether such a clustering can enhance the predictive power of phytoplankton community biomass models.
For my PhD, I examined the prevailing assembly theories in community ecology, and developed comprehensive models of community dynamics with regard to neutral and niche-mediated factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/nanjappa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/nanjappa/</guid>
      <description>Title: Dr Deepak Nanjappa Status: hidden

My research interests are in molecular biology and functional ecology, especially using omics-based methods to understand how microbial systems respond to changing conditions. I am particularly interested in studying gene expression and metabolic pathway, and how their modulation help cells to maintain homeostasis.
My current work involves the study of effects of crude oil spill on phytoplankton community. This involves the analysis of metatranscriptomic data generated during the mesocosm experiments, conducted with natural phytoplankton assemblages and seawater.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/pai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/pai/</guid>
      <description>Title: Akarsh Pai Status: hidden

I am interested in how environmental stressors such as light variability and nitrogen limitation affect the abundance of photosynthetic proteins in Micromonas, a species of picophytoplankton found in the Arctic.
My goal is to learn more about algal culturing along with qualitative and quantitative molecular biology techniques to conduct further analysis on Micromonas as well as other species of microalgae.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/sharpe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/sharpe/</guid>
      <description>Title: Susan Sharpe Status: hidden

I started out in the lab doing a honours project on the metabolic size scaling of Ditylum brightwellii (2009 to 2011). I completed a MSc at Dal examining the transition from unicellular organisms to multicellular organisms using bioinformatics laboratory experiments. Presently I maintain cultures and equipment and assist with various research projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/sheward/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://AndrewIrwin.github.io/mmab-www/people/sheward/</guid>
      <description>Title: Rosie Sheward Status: hidden

My main interest is in the evolution of coccolithophores (unicellular, calcite-producting phytoplankton). My research combines the study of both extinct and living phytoplankton to establish direct links between fossilized phytoplankton remains and present-day species and communities, bringing together approaches and datasets from the traditionally separate fields of phycology and micropaleontology.
I am presently investigating cellular stoichiometry and macromolecular composition in coccolithophores. This contributes to the wider research of lab members into the interactions between cellular resource requirements, resource availability, competitive species interactions, and biogeochemical cycles that ultimately drive the evolution of phytoplankton communities under climate change.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>