<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Marine Macroecology and Biogeochemistry Lab</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Marine Macroecology and Biogeochemistry Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving into the new lab</title>
      <link>/posts/new-lab-2018-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/new-lab-2018-12/</guid>
      <description>We moved into our new lab this week!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MMaB Lab party</title>
      <link>/posts/celebration-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/celebration-2018/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the lab group from our spring celebration. Congratulations in particular to our honours undergradute students: Sally Faulkner, Matt Fyfe, Akarsh Pai, and Catherine Fiset.
It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to get everyone together at the same time, but we did well.
Shown in the figure (L-to-R, F-to-B): Felicia, Catherine, Akarsh, Sally, Ina, Yue, Ruby, Kindy, Rosie, Niall, Zoe, Li, Doug (collaborator), Justin, Andrew, Wei (friend of the lab).
Crispin is in the Democratic Republic of the Congo giving a talk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to our 2018 honours students</title>
      <link>/posts/honours-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/honours-2018/</guid>
      <description>Sally Faulkner, Matt Fyfe, Akarsh Pai, and Catherine Fiset have all completed their honours research projects in the lab. Congratulations to them all on their hard work and impressive accomplishments.
Sally presented her work at a meeting at Memorial University in St John&amp;rsquo;s Newfoundland and won second place for her presentation at the annual Science Atlantic conference, held right here in Sackville this March. Her work is featured in a Mount Allison news story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visitors from TAMUG</title>
      <link>/posts/tamug-visit-day-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tamug-visit-day-trip/</guid>
      <description>Sam Setta and Laura Bretherton visited our lab for a week to work on bioinformatic analysis of some GOMRI experiments.
We always try to be good hosts for our visitors &amp;ndash; this time in addition to lots of hard work this incldued a trip to Hopewell Rocks and Cora&amp;rsquo;s, a favourite local breakfast place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work by Michaël Bradet-Legris featured by Mount Allison</title>
      <link>/posts/bradet-legris-promo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/bradet-legris-promo/</guid>
      <description>The computing and bioinformatic work being done by summer research student Michaël Bradet-Legris was featured in a Mount Allison story this week.
Click here for the full article.
Archive version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer students working in the lab</title>
      <link>/posts/faulker-seawater/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/faulker-seawater/</guid>
      <description>Sally Faulkner, Matt Fyfe, Akarsh Pai, and Catherine Fiset are summer research students working in the lab this summer. They are all busy growing cultures, performing assays, and helping out with lots of tasks around the lab.
This week Sally and Matt got a fun day at the beach to collect seawater for their lab cultures. Even indoor lab scientists need to get some sun now and then!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projected plankton community change featured at the BBC</title>
      <link>/posts/shift-shuffle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/shift-shuffle/</guid>
      <description>Work by Andrew Barton and Charlie Stock (Princeton/GFDL) and Andrew Irwin and Zoe Finkel showing how North Atlantic phytoplankton communities may chnage over the next century was published today in PNAS.
A news story about this work appeared on the BBC website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research meeting</title>
      <link>/posts/gbmf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/gbmf/</guid>
      <description>Gordon and Betty Moore Foundation meeting held at Mount Allison University in Sackville</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research on extinction rates published in Science</title>
      <link>/posts/extinctions-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 09:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/extinctions-science/</guid>
      <description>Fossils helping to identify marine life at high risk of extinction</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing phytoplankton niches</title>
      <link>/posts/pnas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/pnas/</guid>
      <description>New paper on phytoplankton niches published in PNAS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-doctoral research opportunities</title>
      <link>/posts/postdoc1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/postdoc1/</guid>
      <description>Post-doctoral positions available</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Ina Benner&#39;s research featured in student newspaper (The Argosy)</title>
      <link>/posts/benner-argosy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/benner-argosy/</guid>
      <description>Dr Benner&amp;rsquo;s work on phytoplankton evolution was featured in The Argosy this week.
Click here for the full article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gulf of Mexico research project funded</title>
      <link>/posts/gomri/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 11:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/gomri/</guid>
      <description>Mount Allison researcher part of a $7.25 M grant to study effects of Gulf of Mexico oil spill</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zoe Finkel awarded a Canada Research Chair</title>
      <link>/posts/crc-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 13:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/crc-a/</guid>
      <description>Mount Allison researcher in climate change receives national recognition</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>