<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lab on Marine Macroecology and Biogeochemistry Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/lab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lab on Marine Macroecology and Biogeochemistry Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/lab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MMaB Lab party</title>
      <link>/posts/celebration-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/celebration-2018/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the lab group from our spring celebration. Congratulations in particular to our honours undergradute students: Sally Faulkner, Matt Fyfe, Akarsh Pai, and Catherine Fiset.
It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to get everyone together at the same time, but we did well.
Shown in the figure (L-to-R, F-to-B): Felicia, Catherine, Akarsh, Sally, Ina, Yue, Ruby, Kindy, Rosie, Niall, Zoe, Li, Doug (collaborator), Justin, Andrew, Wei (friend of the lab).
Crispin is in the Democratic Republic of the Congo giving a talk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to our 2018 honours students</title>
      <link>/posts/honours-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/honours-2018/</guid>
      <description>Sally Faulkner, Matt Fyfe, Akarsh Pai, and Catherine Fiset have all completed their honours research projects in the lab. Congratulations to them all on their hard work and impressive accomplishments.
Sally presented her work at a meeting at Memorial University in St John&amp;rsquo;s Newfoundland and won second place for her presentation at the annual Science Atlantic conference, held right here in Sackville this March. Her work is featured in a Mount Allison news story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer students working in the lab</title>
      <link>/posts/faulker-seawater/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/faulker-seawater/</guid>
      <description>Sally Faulkner, Matt Fyfe, Akarsh Pai, and Catherine Fiset are summer research students working in the lab this summer. They are all busy growing cultures, performing assays, and helping out with lots of tasks around the lab.
This week Sally and Matt got a fun day at the beach to collect seawater for their lab cultures. Even indoor lab scientists need to get some sun now and then!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research meeting</title>
      <link>/posts/gbmf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/gbmf/</guid>
      <description>Gordon and Betty Moore Foundation meeting held at Mount Allison University in Sackville</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gulf of Mexico research project funded</title>
      <link>/posts/gomri/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 11:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/gomri/</guid>
      <description>Mount Allison researcher part of a $7.25 M grant to study effects of Gulf of Mexico oil spill</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zoe Finkel awarded a Canada Research Chair</title>
      <link>/posts/crc-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 13:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/crc-a/</guid>
      <description>Mount Allison researcher in climate change receives national recognition</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>