<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Marine Microbial Macroecology Lab</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Marine Microbial Macroecology Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About the lab</title>
      <link>/sections/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sections/about/</guid>
      <description>We are an interdisciplinary research group interested in large-scale ecological, evolutionary and biogeochemical phenomena in the oceans. Our primary goal is to understand and anticipate the effects of climate change on marine organisms, specifically phytoplankton using a combination of theoretical and data-driven models, remote-sensed, field and laboratory data, and the fossil record.
The MMaB Lab is located at Dalhousie University in Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada. Members are affiliated with Oceanography and the Mathematics and Statistics departments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank you</title>
      <link>/sections/thanks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sections/thanks/</guid>
      <description>We thank NSERC, CRC, NBIF, CFI, Mount Allison University, Dalhousie University, the Gordon and Betty Moore Foundation, the Simons Foundation, Ace-net, NASA, MITACS, and the Marjorie Young Bell foundation for generous support of our research programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving into the new lab</title>
      <link>/posts/new-lab-2018-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/new-lab-2018-12/</guid>
      <description>We moved into our new lab this week!
  Photo of the new lab shortly after starting to move in.   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MMaB Lab party</title>
      <link>/posts/celebration-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/celebration-2018/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the lab group from our spring celebration. Congratulations in particular to our honours undergradute students: Sally Faulkner, Matt Fyfe, Akarsh Pai, and Catherine Fiset.
It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to get everyone together at the same time, but we did well.
Shown in the figure (L-to-R, F-to-B): Felicia, Catherine, Akarsh, Sally, Ina, Yue, Ruby, Kindy, Rosie, Niall, Zoe, Li, Doug (collaborator), Justin, Andrew, Wei (friend of the lab).
Crispin is in the Democratic Republic of the Congo giving a talk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to our 2018 honours students</title>
      <link>/posts/honours-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/honours-2018/</guid>
      <description>Sally Faulkner, Matt Fyfe, Akarsh Pai, and Catherine Fiset have all completed their honours research projects in the lab. Congratulations to them all on their hard work and impressive accomplishments.
Sally presented her work at a meeting at Memorial University in St John&amp;rsquo;s Newfoundland and won second place for her presentation at the annual Science Atlantic conference, held right here in Sackville this March. Her work is featured in a Mount Allison news story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visitors from TAMUG</title>
      <link>/posts/tamug-visit-day-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tamug-visit-day-trip/</guid>
      <description>Sam Setta and Laura Bretherton visited our lab for a week to work on bioinformatic analysis of some GOMRI experiments.
We always try to be good hosts for our visitors &amp;ndash; this time in addition to lots of hard work this incldued a trip to Hopewell Rocks and Cora&amp;rsquo;s, a favourite local breakfast place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work by Michaël Bradet-Legris featured by Mount Allison</title>
      <link>/posts/bradet-legris-promo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/bradet-legris-promo/</guid>
      <description>The computing and bioinformatic work being done by summer research student Michaël Bradet-Legris was featured in a Mount Allison story this week.
Click here for the full article.
Archive version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer students working in the lab</title>
      <link>/posts/faulker-seawater/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/faulker-seawater/</guid>
      <description>Sally Faulkner, Matt Fyfe, Akarsh Pai, and Catherine Fiset are summer research students working in the lab this summer. They are all busy growing cultures, performing assays, and helping out with lots of tasks around the lab.
This week Sally and Matt got a fun day at the beach to collect seawater for their lab cultures. Even indoor lab scientists need to get some sun now and then!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projected plankton community change featured at the BBC</title>
      <link>/posts/shift-shuffle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/shift-shuffle/</guid>
      <description>Work by Andrew Barton and Charlie Stock (Princeton/GFDL) and Andrew Irwin and Zoe Finkel showing how North Atlantic phytoplankton communities may chnage over the next century was published today in PNAS.
A news story about this work appeared on the BBC website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research meeting</title>
      <link>/posts/gbmf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/gbmf/</guid>
      <description>Gordon and Betty Moore Foundation meeting held at Mount Allison University in Sackville</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research on extinction rates published in Science</title>
      <link>/posts/extinctions-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2015 09:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/extinctions-science/</guid>
      <description>Fossils helping to identify marine life at high risk of extinction</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing phytoplankton niches</title>
      <link>/posts/pnas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2015 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/pnas/</guid>
      <description>New paper on phytoplankton niches published in PNAS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-doctoral research opportunities</title>
      <link>/posts/postdoc1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2015 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/postdoc1/</guid>
      <description>Post-doctoral positions available</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Ina Benner&#39;s research featured in student newspaper (The Argosy)</title>
      <link>/posts/benner-argosy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/benner-argosy/</guid>
      <description>Dr Benner&amp;rsquo;s work on phytoplankton evolution was featured in The Argosy this week.
Click here for the full article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gulf of Mexico research project funded</title>
      <link>/posts/gomri/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2015 11:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/gomri/</guid>
      <description>Mount Allison researcher part of a $7.25 M grant to study effects of Gulf of Mexico oil spill</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zoe Finkel awarded a Canada Research Chair</title>
      <link>/posts/crc-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 13:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/crc-a/</guid>
      <description>Mount Allison researcher in climate change receives national recognition</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/images/</guid>
      <description>Title: Images Gallery: {photo}images/people Status: hidden</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Akarsh Pai</title>
      <link>/people/pai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/pai/</guid>
      <description>I am interested in how environmental stressors such as light variability and nitrogen limitation affect the abundance of photosynthetic proteins in Micromonas, a species of picophytoplankton found in the Arctic.
My goal is to learn more about algal culturing along with qualitative and quantitative molecular biology techniques to conduct further analysis on Micromonas as well as other species of microalgae.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aneri Garg</title>
      <link>/people/garg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/garg/</guid>
      <description>I am interested in the cellular macromolecular composition of phytoplankton, and how various taxa change their composition during and after periods of environmental stress.
Currently I am quantifying the macromolecular composition of the species Micromonas at various points along its growth cycle. This microalgae has a broad pan-Arctic distribution and is present throughout the year. Their ecology and composition will be particularly important to track in response to arctic climate change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catherine Fiset</title>
      <link>/people/fiset/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/fiset/</guid>
      <description>I am a fourth-year honours student in biology. I am interested in how variations in the macromolecular composition of micro- and macroalgae impact marine ecosystems.
In the last year, I have done research on macroalgae. I first looked at the biases in the methods used to quantify macroalgae macromolecular content, and am now investigating the differences in average macromolecular composition between the three macroalgae phyla: the Chlorophyta, Rhodophyta, and Ochrophyta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact information</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>Zoe V. Finkel
Department of Oceanography
Dalhousie University
Halifax, NS, B3H 4R2
Canada
zfinkel at dal dot ca
+1 (506) 364-2615
Andrew J. Irwin
Dept. of Mathematics and Statistics
Dalhousie University
Halifax, NB, B3H 4R2
Canada
a.irwin at dal dot ca
+1 (506) 364-5747
 See the Members page for more email addresses.
Find us on google maps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Chris Brown</title>
      <link>/people/brown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/brown/</guid>
      <description>I am interested in biochemical processes that dramatically alter the environment, such as photosynthesis, nitrogen fixation, metal detoxification and methanogenesis.
Presently I am working on quantitative methods for proteins, carbohydrates, and nucleic acids. I also operate a small biotech company that I founded with two colleagues, called Environmental Proteomics. We develop proteomics tools and methods for plant sciences, oceanography, and a variety of microbial processes.
For my PhD I studied the quotas and fates of macromolecular pools, including photosynthetic proteins and subcellular DNA fractions, in phytoplankton infected by viruses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Crispin M. Mutshinda</title>
      <link>/people/mutshinda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/mutshinda/</guid>
      <description>I am interested in the interplay of random drift and niche-mediated (non-neutral) processes in driving the dynamics and structure of ecological communities.
Currently I am designing hierarchical Bayesian models and Markov Chain Monte-Carlo algorithms to identify potential trait-based phytoplankton clusters and investigate whether such a clustering can enhance the predictive power of phytoplankton community biomass models.
For my PhD, I examined the prevailing assembly theories in community ecology, and developed comprehensive models of community dynamics with regard to neutral and niche-mediated factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Deepak Nanjappa</title>
      <link>/people/nanjappa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/nanjappa/</guid>
      <description>My research interests are in molecular biology and functional ecology, especially using omics-based methods to understand how microbial systems respond to changing conditions. I am particularly interested in studying gene expression and metabolic pathway, and how their modulation help cells to maintain homeostasis.
My current work involves the study of effects of crude oil spill on phytoplankton community. This involves the analysis of metatranscriptomic data generated during the mesocosm experiments, conducted with natural phytoplankton assemblages and seawater.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Ina Benner</title>
      <link>/people/benner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/benner/</guid>
      <description>I am interested in understanding how single cell organisms can evolve to changes in climate.
Presently I am determining the potential of arctic phytoplankton to evolve to changing temperature.
For my PhD I worked on the utilization of organic nutrients in phytoplankton at the Alfred Wegner Institute in Bremerhaven, Germany. I&amp;rsquo;ve also worked at the Romberg Tiburon Center for Environmental Studies in San Francisco on the adaptation of calcifying phytoplankton to temperature and carbon dioxide concentration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Justin Liefer</title>
      <link>/people/liefer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/liefer/</guid>
      <description>I am interested in the physiology and ecology of aquatic microbes, including their production of toxins or useful natural products.
Presently I am studying how differences in macromolecular composition and energy storage among microalgae affect their growth and stress tolerance.
For my PhD, I studied coastal biogeochemistry, phytoplankton ecology, and toxic algal blooms at the Dauphin Island Sea Lab in Dauphin Island, USA. I continued this work as a postdoctoral researcher at the Univ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Niall McGinty</title>
      <link>/people/mcginty/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/mcginty/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m broadly interested in marine spatial ecology and time series analysis of pelagic ecosystems ranging from the micro- to the macroscale. I am particularly interested in the ways in which organisms (especially zooplankton) respond to changes in the climate regarding their distribution, niches and timing.
My PhD was conducted in the NUI Galway where I examined the regional scale variability of plankton within Irish waters over the last 50 years, and tried to put into context these findings with the large scale shifts observed across the North Atlantic during that time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Ruby Hu</title>
      <link>/people/hu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/hu/</guid>
      <description>As a chemist, my expertise covers a broad spectrum of capabilities including (1) chemistry, such as inorganic nanoparticles, organic synthesis, analytical chemistry especially the nitrate optode in microplate and analysis of biogenic silica; (2) biology, such as purification and taxonomy of fossilized diatom in sediment, culturing, automate fossilized diatom sample analysis with FlowCam.
My new goal is to learn more about assay analysis of microalgal cells. In addition, I will maintain cultures, equipment and the laboratory in good condition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Yue Liang</title>
      <link>/people/liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/liang/</guid>
      <description>I am interested in understanding physiological and biochemical responses in microalgae to environmental changes using systemic biological approaches.
Presently I am working on RNA-seq based transcriptomic analyses on two closely related diatom strains cultured under three different temperatures.
For my PhD, I studied useful natural microalgal lipids on several aspects including structural characterization, biosynthesis pathway identification, and investigation of their metabolic regulation under stressed conditions at Tokyo University of Agriculture and Technology in Japan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Zhi-Ping Mei</title>
      <link>/people/mei/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/mei/</guid>
      <description>I am a biological oceanographer interested in understanding how plankton communities in marine and aquatic ecosystems form and change with environmental change due to natural or anthropogenic disturbance, and its consequence to the biogeochemical processes of the ecosystems.
I use quantitative approaches to mining the observational data, and build models to investigate the diversity and structure of plankton communities in a changing environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justin Laforest</title>
      <link>/people/laforest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/laforest/</guid>
      <description>I am interested in researching the effects of global climate change on marine phytoplankton, to analyze the resulting climate feedbacks related to global carbon fixation.
Presently I am researching different traits amongst marine diatoms in effort to determine why some diatoms form chains, in conjunction to the method in which they do so. Understanding the reasoning of chain forming diatoms will provide further information of diatom life cycles, and their predicted future success within the effects of a globally changing climate system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kindy Houinato</title>
      <link>/people/houinato/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/houinato/</guid>
      <description>I am a fourth-year student completing an Honour in Economics and a Major in Environmental Science. This summer, I am interested in understanding the advantage and disadvantages associated with the different chains formed by diatoms. Literature suggests that the shape and length of chains appear to be determined by several environmental factors, such as effectiveness of grazer defense (Sournia 1982; Smetacek et al. 2004; Bergkvist et al. 2012), adjustment of buoyancy (Smayda &amp;amp; Boleyn 1966; Smayda 1970; Takabayashi et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab members</title>
      <link>/members/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/members/</guid>
      <description>Email addresses for most lab members are listed below.
Zoe V. Finkel Oceanography, Canada Research Chair in Marine Microbial Macroecology
My research interests focus on the eco-physiological controls of phytoplankton community structure, feedbacks between phytoplankton community structure and climate change, and the macroevolutionary history of phytoplankton communities. (Google scholar, Researcher ID B-9626-2008, ORCID 0000-0003-4212-3917, email: zfinkel at dal.ca.)
Andrew J. Irwin Mathematics &amp;amp; Statistics
I use mathematical and statistical models to study the marine biosphere, phytoplankton growth, and environmental influences on the distribution of phytoplankton in the ocean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Margaux Daly</title>
      <link>/people/daly/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/daly/</guid>
      <description>I am interested in understanding how phytoplankton respond to changing arctic conditions. I am currently working to understand how changes in environmental conditions such as light and temperature influence the evolutionary potential of Arctic and Antarctic Phaeocystis species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matthew Hamilton Fyfe</title>
      <link>/people/fyfe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/fyfe/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m interested in the macromolecular content of phytoplankton, and am spending the summer learning the techniques for determining such data. I will be applying this knowledge to the diatom Didymospenia geminata once we&amp;rsquo;ve extracted samples of it from New Brunswick rivers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications from our lab</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>Publications and citations from Google Scholar (Irwin, Finkel), ORCID (Irwin, Finkel), Europe PubMed Central (Irwin), and Researcher ID (Irwin, Finkel).
For each paper, the title links to a PDF copy of the article and the doi links to the journal&amp;rsquo;s copy of the paper. Supplementary information is provided under separate links where applicable.
2019  JD Liefer, A Garg, MH Fyfe, AJ Irwin, I Benner, CM Brown, MJ Follows, AW Omta, ZV Finkel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research positions</title>
      <link>/opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/opportunities/</guid>
      <description>We are looking to recruit researchers to join us at Dalhousie University in Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada.
We are looking for independent, creative scientists with a background in biological oceanography or plankton ecology and skills in one or more of the following areas: bioinformatics, particularly transcriptomics in non-model microbial eukaryotes, computational data analysis in macroecology, Bayesian statistics, phytoplankton culturing, biochemical assays, and molecular techniques.
Research opportunity for undergraduate students Opportunities are available for enthusiastic undergraduate students that would like research experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rosie Sheward</title>
      <link>/people/sheward/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/sheward/</guid>
      <description>My main interest is in the evolution of coccolithophores (unicellular, calcite-producting phytoplankton). My research combines the study of both extinct and living phytoplankton to establish direct links between fossilized phytoplankton remains and present-day species and communities, bringing together approaches and datasets from the traditionally separate fields of phycology and micropaleontology.
I am presently investigating cellular stoichiometry and macromolecular composition in coccolithophores. This contributes to the wider research of lab members into the interactions between cellular resource requirements, resource availability, competitive species interactions, and biogeochemical cycles that ultimately drive the evolution of phytoplankton communities under climate change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sally Faulkner</title>
      <link>/people/faulkner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/faulkner/</guid>
      <description>I am interested in understanding how the macromolecular composition of microalgae is related to environmental and biotic conditions.
Presently I am studying the effect of nitrogen and phosphorus limitation on macromolecular composition of a size range of centric diatom species.
For my BSc I am completing a double major of Biology and Environmental Science (Hons.). I have a strong interest in biological oceanography, geology, and theatre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Susan Sharpe</title>
      <link>/people/sharpe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/sharpe/</guid>
      <description>I started out in the lab doing a honours project on the metabolic size scaling of Ditylum brightwellii (2009 to 2011). I completed a MSc at Dal examining the transition from unicellular organisms to multicellular organisms using bioinformatics laboratory experiments. Presently I maintain cultures and equipment and assist with various research projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thomas Hammond</title>
      <link>/people/hammond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/people/hammond/</guid>
      <description>I am interested in the statistical processes which are required for genome sequence analysis and how phytoplankton adapt when exposed to oil rich environments. I am currently working on reconciling the variances in data reporting and recording from the many different phytoplankton collection centers across the world.
I am a recent graduate of Mount Allison and am looking to discover the various fields which can benefit from regression and time series analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Marine Macroecology and Biogeochemistry Lab</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>We are an interdisciplinary research group interested in large-scale ecological, evolutionary and biogeochemical phenomena in the oceans. Our primary goal is to understand and anticipate the effects of climate change on marine organisms, specifically phytoplankton using a combination of theoretical and data-driven models, remote-sensed, field and laboratory data, and the fossil record.
The MMaB Lab is located at Dalhousie University in Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada. Members are affiliated with Oceanography and the Mathematics and Statistics departments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>